<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<site url="http://www.whatisbiodiesel.org/">
	<info>
		<assets url="assets/">
			<asset medium="swf" url="swfmodules/" />
			<asset medium="image" url="img/" />
			<asset medium="movplayer" url="movplayer/" />
			<asset medium="video" url="video/" />
		</assets>
	</info>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title><![CDATA[Introduction]]></title>
			<type><![CDATA[IntroPane]]></type>
			<content loc="internal" medium="text">
				<data><![CDATA[As gasoline prices in the United States reach record highs, alternative fuels such as ethanol, electricity, hydrogen and biodiesel are being looked at as possible replacements for petroleum-based fuels. Biodiesel is unique among the alternative fuels because it can be made from used vegetable oils or animal fats, it will run in unmodified diesel vehicles, and it can be produced by anyone willing to learn how. This site explores how biodiesel is made, why it appeals to people who view it as a sustainable alternative to gasoline, and how biodiesel compares with other alternative fuels.]]></data>
			</content>
			<content loc="external" medium="image">
				<url><![CDATA[introphoto.jpg]]></url>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title><![CDATA[Making Biodiesel]]></title>
			<type><![CDATA[InfographicPane]]></type>
			<content loc="external" medium="swf">
				<url><![CDATA[makingbiodiesel/biodieselInfoGraphic.swf]]></url>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title><![CDATA[Sustainable Biodiesel]]></title>
			<type><![CDATA[VideoPane]]></type>
			<content loc="external" medium="movplayer">
				<url><![CDATA[movplayer.swf]]></url>
			</content>
			<content loc="external" medium="video">
				<url><![CDATA[biodieselvideo.m4v]]></url>
			</content>
			<content loc="internal" medium="text">
				<data><![CDATA[Located in the small town of Moncure, North Carolina, Piedmont Biofuels Cooperative is a member-owned organization formed to encourage sustainable living through the use of renewable biofuels. In keeping with its dedication to sustainability, Piedmont Biofuels Cooperative makes biodiesel from used vegetable oil collected from area restaurants. Piedmont Biofuels Cooperative offers its members the opportunity to learn about biodiesel by helping to make a batch at their Tuesday fuel-making nights. Members who help make biodiesel on Tuesday night are entitled to a share of the finished fuel at a reduced price.]]></data>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title><![CDATA[Comparing Alternatives]]></title>
			<type><![CDATA[InfographicPane]]></type>
		<content loc="external" medium="swf">
				<url><![CDATA[alternatives/alternatives.swf]]></url>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title><![CDATA[Looking Ahead]]></title>
			<type><![CDATA[OutroPane]]></type>
			<content loc='internal' medium="text">
				<data><![CDATA[Record high gasoline prices have increased consumer attention toward alternative fuels, but while politicians call for independence from fossil fuels, it is unclear what the solution is. Each alternative fuel has its own benefits and costs, as explained in the "Comparing Alternatives" section of this site, but no alternative has distinguished itself as the best option. Currently ethanol and biodiesel are options because they are both produced from plant matter. Fuels created using biological matter are known collectively as biofuels. Biofuels are popular because they allow farmers to grow food for fuel, which some view as positive because it bolsters the agriculture industry. However, as more farmers began growing crops for biofuels, new problems emerged.
In 2008, food prices began rising as the cost of gasoline reached new highs. Part of the increase in food prices came from the higher cost of fueling farm equipment, but some blame has been placed on the use of crops to produce fuel. Corn prices nearly doubled as farmers found that they could sell their crops at higher prices for ethanol production. In the United States, a subsidy for farmers growing corn for ethanol made food for fuel production even more appealing. Since corn is also used to feed farm animals, the prices of foods made from those animals also increased. Soybean prices increased somewhat since more soybeans were being used for commercial biodiesel production. Higher world food prices impacted developing countries greatly not only because food costs cut into incomes in those countries, but also because international food aid became more scarce.
In addition to increasing food prices, studies of commercial biofuel production point out that the energy and environmental costs of producing biofuel are often not taken into account in discussions of the benefits of biofuels such as ethanol and biodiesel. Unlike Piedmont Biofuels Cooperative, profiled in the "Sustainable Biodiesel" section, most commercial biodiesel producers do not base their operations on environmentally sustainable practices. Commercial biodiesel is made almost entirely from virgin soybean crops rather than used vegetable oils or animal fats. The long term sustainability of biodiesel production from used vegetable oils or animal fats is uncertain as more independent producers vie for sources such as waste cooking oil from restaurants. Despite these controversies, biofuel production is on the rise internationally.
Biofuels are especially popular in South American countries where crops that had been cultivated there for years are being turned into biofuels. In addition to corn, sugar cane is made into ethanol, and a variety of bean crops are made into biodiesel. For example, the Brazilian government has mandated that all diesel fuel contain at least two percent biodiesel (B2) in 2008 and five percent biodiesel (B5) by 2012. Additionally, Brazil has created government programs to increase ethanol production. Argentina, Colombia and Peru started their own biofuel initiatives. At the same time, the increased concern over world food prices is forcing these countries to reexamine their biofuel energy policies. Some countries have even placed restrictions on the amount of crops that can be used to make biofuels. India and China in particular cautious about farming for biofuels because they have become dependent on food imports which are becoming more expensive.
So what is the future of biofuels and biodiesel given these issues? Researchers are looking for better ways to produce biofuels. A lot of current research is exploring ways that algae can be used to produce biodiesel. Certain types of algae produce high levels of oil, and researchers are trying to breed an algae that produces a maximum amount of oil for the energy put into growing it. Producing algae for biodiesel would still require the use of land for cultivation, so attention is being paid toward how algae farming could be integrated successfully with other agricultural practices. In other countries a plant called jatropha is being examined because of its seed's high oil yield and the plant's resistance to drought and pests.
Though these options are not ready for commercial use, the biodiesel production techniques being researched today could provide a path for biodiesel to lead us away from fossil fuels. However, there is no telling how long it might take for biodiesel to mature into a viable alternative fuel, and another alternative fuel may prove more viable in the interim. For now, biodiesel is just one possibility on the road to energy independence.]]></data>
			</content>
			<content loc="external" medium="image">
				<url><![CDATA[outrophoto.jpg]]></url>
			</content>
		</section>
	</sections>
</site>