<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<site url="http://www.whatisbiodiesel.org/">
	<info>
		<assets url="assets/">
			<asset medium="swf" url="swfmodules/" />
			<asset medium="image" url="img/" />
			<asset medium="movplayer" url="movplayer/" />
			<asset medium="video" url="video/" />
		</assets>
	</info>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title><![CDATA[Introduction]]></title>
			<type><![CDATA[IntroPane]]></type>
			<content loc="internal" medium="text">
				<data><![CDATA[As gasoline prices in the United States reach record highs, alternative fuels such as ethanol, electricity, hydrogen and biodiesel are being looked at as possible replacements for petroleum-based fuels. Biodiesel is unique among the alternative fuels because it can be made from used vegetable oils or animal fats, it will run in unmodified diesel vehicles, and it can be produced by anyone willing to learn how. This site explores how biodiesel is made, why it appeals to people who view it as a sustainable alternative to gasoline, and how biodiesel compares with other alternative fuels.]]></data>
			</content>
			<content loc="external" medium="image">
				<url><![CDATA[introphoto.jpg]]></url>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title><![CDATA[Making Biodiesel]]></title>
			<type><![CDATA[InfographicPane]]></type>
			<content loc="external" medium="swf">
				<url><![CDATA[makingbiodiesel/biodieselInfoGraphic.swf]]></url>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title><![CDATA[Sustainable Biodiesel]]></title>
			<type><![CDATA[VideoPane]]></type>
			<content loc="external" medium="movplayer">
				<url><![CDATA[movplayer.swf]]></url>
			</content>
			<content loc="external" medium="video">
				<url><![CDATA[biodieselvideo.m4v]]></url>
			</content>
			<content loc="internal" medium="text">
				<data><![CDATA[Located in the small town of Moncure, North Carolina, Piedmont Biofuels Cooperative is a member-owned organization formed to encourage sustainable living through the use of renewable biofuels. In keeping with its dedication to sustainability, Piedmont Biofuels Cooperative makes biodiesel from used vegetable oil collected from area restaurants. Piedmont Biofuels Cooperative offers its members the opportunity to learn about biodiesel by helping to make a batch at their Tuesday fuel-making nights. Members who help make biodiesel on Tuesday night are entitled to a share of the finished fuel at a reduced price.]]></data>
			</content>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title><![CDATA[Comparing Alternatives]]></title>
			<type><![CDATA[InfographicPane]]></type>
		<content loc="external" medium="swf">
				<url><![CDATA[alternatives/alternatives.swf]]></url>
			</content>
		</section>
	</sections>
</site>